eia.gov 2017-12-31

# About EIA - Policies - U.S. Energy Information Administration (EIA)

#### Privacy statement

This website (<http://www.eia.gov/>) is provided as a public energy information service of the U.S. Energy Information Administration. 

EIA.gov utilizes web measurement software tools in order to improve the efficiency of our website and to provide a better user experience for our customers. If you visit this site to read or download information, you should know that EIA collects and stores a standard set of Internet-related information, such as an Internet Protocol (IP) address, the date and time, the type of browser and operating system used, the page(s) visited, and if you linked to the EIA website from another website, the address of that website. 

The Office of Management and Budget (OMB) classifies this as a Tier 2 usage since we utilize multi-session web measurement technologies that do not collect any personally identifiable information (PII). These technologies anonymously track how visitors interact with EIA.gov, including where they came from, what they did on the site, and whether they completed any pre-determined tasks while on the site. 

We use Google Analytics and IBM's NetInsight web measurement technologies. This information is used to optimize our website; improve our user interface and ensure our content meets the needs of our customers. No personally identifiable information is collected, so the anonymity of the user is protected. The measurement data that is collected is only retained for as long as is needed for proper analysis and optimization of the website and is accessible only to employees whose position necessitates it. 

Since disabling this web measurement technology requires you to modify your individual browser settings, it is enabled by default. If you wish to opt-out from these web measurement technologies, you can find instructions for changing your browser settings at <http://www.usa.gov/optout_instructions.shtml>. Google also provides a browser plug-in that will allow you to opt-out of all Google Analytics measurements, which you can find at <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>. Please note that opting-out in no way effects your access to content or how you see the site. 

#### If you send us personal information and/or subscribe to EIA's e-mail notification system (e-lists)

If you choose to provide us with personal information such as submitting information through the website on our Feedback page ([www.eia.gov/about/feedback](http://www.eia.gov/about/feedback/)), e-mail subscription lists, or in an e-mail to EIA's Information Center, or to any EIA email (@eia.gov) we use that information to respond to your message and to help us get you the information you have requested. We do not collect personal information for any purpose other than to respond to you. EIA does not give, sell, or transfer personal information to third parties, unless required by law, such as the Freedom of Information Act. 

#### If you participate in EIA's social media activities

EIA is committed to expanding access to its information and engaging its customers and stakeholders. One of the key ways we seek to accomplish this is through the use of third-party social media websites and applications. We do not collect or request personally identifiable information through these outlets, but may occasionally come into contact with unsolicited PII due to circumstances beyond our control. As a result, we reserve the right to moderate or remove comments that offer personally identifiable information such as address, phone number or social security number in a public manner. No PII will be retained in our system or shared with outside parties.

#### Security, intrusion, and detection

For site security purposes, and to ensure this service remains available to all users, this Government computer system employs software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage.

#### Operations security program

The U.S. Energy Information Administration maintains a program (Operations Security [OPSEC]) that is designed to protect information collected in EIA's surveys. This Program takes the form of various elements such as: staff security training, pre-hire certification, and integrity of EIA data systems, fair practice data disclosure policies, and the physical security of all sensitive unclassified EIA data. If you have any questions concerning this program, please contact Keith Rapoza, phone (202) 586-2626.

#### Links to other sites

Our website has links to many other websites including government (Federal, State, local, and international) agencies, universities, trade associations, energy companies, and selected other websites. All links that navigate you away from _www.eia.gov_ are denoted by the  icon. If you navigate to another site, you will be subject to the privacy policy of that site.

#### Security policy

This website is part of a federal computer system used to accomplish federal functions. The U.S. Energy Information Administration continuously monitors this website for security purposes to ensure it remains available to all users and to protect information in the system. By accessing this website, you are expressly consenting to these monitoring activities. 

Unauthorized attempts to defeat or circumvent security features, to use the system for other than intended purposes, to deny service to authorized users, to access, obtain, alter, damage, or destroy information, or otherwise to interfere with the system or its operation is prohibited. Evidence of such acts may be disclosed to law enforcement authorities and result in criminal prosecution under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act of 1996 (Pub. L. 104-294), (18 U.S.C. 1030), or other applicable criminal laws.

#### Automated retrieval program (robot) activity

EIA is committed to providing data promptly and according to established schedules. Therefore any automated retrieval program (commonly referred to as a "robot" or "bot") that excessively accesses information from EIA's website is prohibited. Excessive robot activity on EIA's website can cause delays and interfere with other customers' timely access to information.

EIA will block robots that are accessing the website in any way that EIA considers excessive or malicious, including robots that attempt to access or download survey information multiple times per second with resulting degradation of service to others. EIA also reserves the right to block robots that do not contain contact information that can be used to contact the owner. Blocking may occur in real time. 

**NOTE:** Robots using a specific IP address instead of an official EIA URL (examples: www.eia.gov or ir.eia.gov) are at risk for not receiving data promptly at prescribed times.

#### **Trouble accessing the EIA website?**

EIA uses industry standard "blackhole" lists, maintained by public and private institutions in the larger Internet community, to defensively block access to our web servers. Please understand that EIA does not maintain these lists and we cannot remove you from them. We suggest you alert your network security officer (for businesses and organizations) or your internet service provider (for individuals).
